Lauren A. Mills Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Lauren A. Mills Papers.
1986-1993
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Mills, Lauren A.
3.75 linear feet.
MSS19940009
The collection contains sketches, illustrations, correspondence, manuscripts, drafts, dummies and proofs for six books illustrated by Lauren Mills. Of these six books, Ms. Mills authored two as well as illustrating them. The collection includes The Rag Coat, Tatterhood and the Hobgoblins, A Norwegian Folktale, Where the Towers Pierce the Sky (jacket only), Anne of Green Gables, Elfabet, An ABC of Elves (CLC C1842), and The Tsar's Promise.
Biography
Scope and Content
The collection contains sketches, illustrations, correspondence, manuscripts, drafts, dummies and proofs for six books illustrated by Lauren Mills. Of these six books, Ms. Mills authored two as well as illustrating them. The collection includes The Rag Coat, Tatterhood and the Hobgoblins, A Norwegian Folktale, Where the Towers Pierce the Sky (jacket only), Anne of Green Gables, Elfabet, An ABC of Elves (CLC C1842), and The Tsar's Promise.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of children's literature and associated artwork. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Bibliography
Writings by the Author
The Rag Coat, Little, Brown & Company, 1991.
Tatterhood and the Hobgoblins, A Norwegian Folktale, Little, Brown & Company, 1993.
Fairy Wings, Little, Brown & Company, 1995.
The Fairy Doll, Little, Brown & Company, 1997.
The Book of Little Folk, Faery Stories & Poems from Around the World, Penguin Putnam Books for Young Readers 1997.
Ebony, Little, Brown & Company, 1998.
The Dog Prince, Little, Brown & Company, 1999.
Illustrator
George MacDonald. At the Back of the North Wind, David R. Godine Publisher, 1988.
Marie Goodwin. Where the Towers Pierce the Sky, Simon and Schuster, 1989.
L.M. Montgomery. Anne of Green Gables, David R. Godine Publisher, 1989.
Jane Yolen. Elfabet, An ABC of Elves, Little, Brown & Company, 1990.
Robert SanSouci. The Tsar's Promise, Penguin Putnam for Young Readers 1992.
Cindy Kane. The Goblin Baby, Penguin Putnam Books for Young Readers 1999.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Children's literature, American 20th century.; Children's literature--Illustrations.; Children's literature--Connecticut authors.; Children's literature--Connecticut illustrators.; Illustrated children's books.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Photographs.; Artwork.; Illustrations.; Manuscripts.; Galley proofs.
Occupations:
Illustrator.; Author.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Ms. Mills in 1994.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Papers, 1986-1993
  - Anne of Green Gables, L.M. Montgomery, 1989
    - Sketches (Box 3:, Folder 2)
    - Illustrations (watercolor) (Box 3:, Folder 3)
    - Cover proof and dust jacket (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Elfabet, An ABC of Elves, Jane Yolen, 1990
    - Manuscript (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Dummy (2) (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - Revisions (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - Sketches (Box 3:, Folder 8)
    - Sketches and proofs (Box 3:, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
    - Illustration (watercolor) (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - The Rag Coat, 1991
    - Manuscript, 1988-1989 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
    - Dummy (3), Revisions, Layout (Box 1:, Folder 13)
    - Sketches and proofs (Box 3:, Folder 14)
    - Illustrations (watercolor) (Box 3:, Folder 15)
    - Color boards (2) (Box OS)
  - Tatterhood and the Hobgoblins, A Norwegian Folktale, 1993
    - Draft (Box 2:, Folder 22)
    - Manuscript, 1986-1988 (Box 2:, Folder 23)
    - Revisions, 1988 (Box 2:, Folder 24)
    - Dummy, 1991 (Box 2:, Folder 25)
    - Paste up (Box 2:, Folder 26)
    - Sketches (Box 3:, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, 1988, 1992 (Box 2:, Folder 28)
    - Photographs (Box 2:, Folder 29)
    - Reviews, 1993 (Box 2:, Folder 30)
  - The Tsar's Promise, Robert SanSouci, 1992
    - Drafts (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - Dummies (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - Sketches (Box 3:, Folder 18)
    - Sketches and proofs (Box 3:, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
    - Photographs (Box 1:, Folder 21)
  - Where the Towers Pierce the Sky, Marie Goodwin, 1989
    - Dust Jacket (Box 1:, Folder 1)